Contact

dinegerald10@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ geraldinegerald (LinkedIn) codesbydine.netlify.app/ (Portfolio) github.com/codesbydine/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Backpack

Jest

FTP software

Languages

Zulu (Native or Bilingual) English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Full Stack Web Dev Bootcamp Learning PHP

Reactjs Tutorial

Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript

Front-End Software Engineering Virtual Experience Programme

Geraldine Gerald

Software Developer at Upwork

City of Johannesburg, Gauteng, South Africa

Summary

I am a second year Bachelor of science in Software Engineering student, I am a part time software developer with one year experience.

I have a passion for web development and mobile application development, I am a C# developer however I have skills in PHP, Python, Flutter, React and many more.

I have attached my previous projects onto my GitHub account.

I aspire to be an AI engineer/ Machine Learning Engineer.

Experience

Upwork Software Developer May 2022 - Present (5 months)

City of Johannesburg, Gauteng, South Africa

I am a part time software developer and I work remotely. I have worked on website creation using WordPress, Laravel and React, I have worked on projects that build websites based of ideas from other existing websites.

I mostly specialise in web design using UI, UX, HTML and CSS to design the websites based on the user requirements. I would either completely customise a new page or improve an already existing page.

I work hand in hand with my clients providing constant feedback while also receiving requirements from the user, this helps me to fully build a website that suits the client's needs.

UCPro

1 year 1 month

Web Development Intern

September 2021 - Present (1 year 1 month)

I began my web development internship in September 2021, I was giving the opportunity to be introduced into the web development industry and I grow my experience with the internship.

I worked mostly on E-commerce websites both back-end and front-end, I learnt the fundamentals of full stack web development and was introduced to tools such as Git, Docker, Postman and so many more.

I was given the opportunity to work with other developers around the world and we worked in a Scrum agile development environment.

I have attached all my projects on my GitHub account.

Android Developer Intern February 2022 - Present (8 months)

Transitioning from web development to android development during my internship was an amazing experience.

I was introduced to android development using Android studio and Flutter, using my full stack web development knowledge it was simple for me to start working on a full stack application.

The project I worked on was a hospital application that allowed users to order medicine online and book appointments with certain doctors.

We firstly started off by creating the website for the hospital then later on moved on to creating the android application.

I worked with the UI/UX of the application, insuring that the front-end of the application was effective and attractive to the user.

Forage

Frontend Developer

August 2022 - September 2022 (2 months)

I joined an online virtual program that allowed me to enhance my front-end development skills, I was exposed to three important skills "Javascript, React and Jest Testing".

I worked on a project that is avaliable on my github account, within this project I have incorported some skills that I have learned. I am excited to put into work my new skills that I have learnt.

DevSavvy

Bootcamp Attendee

January 2022 - February 2022 (2 months)

This bootcamp is a web developement course that I joined with the company, we were given an instructor who walked us through everything we needed to know regarding web development.

I got the chance to be given a platform to grow my web development skills and learn new ones as well.

Education

Eduvos

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Software Engineering · (2021 - 2023)